MARIANO BENEDETTINI

FNGINFFRING I FADER

9

Buenos Aires, Argentina

+54 9 11 21569988

mbenedettini@gmail.com

in <u>marianobenedettini</u>

mbenedettini

marianobe.cc

ABOUT ME

Engineering Leader with a very strong technical background, always hands-on and product oriented. I have experience in a variety of organizations in the US, ranging from small startups (Glide) to Fortune 500 Companies (Compass), plus working as a Software Engineer for ventures all around the globe.

EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager & LatAm Coordinator Compass (US)

April 2021 - May 2023

I had a double role, first being an Engineering Manager of teams closely related to Glide, supporting a group of 12 people, and then growing the Argentina based team from 10 people to 30+, assembling a recruitment team along the way.

- Created an Android team that built and launched the Glide Android app from scratch.
- Led the implementation of data privacy policies and tools for a successful compliance of CCPA for Glide. This included the complete implementation of DataGrail to help manage and process requests.
- Managed teams related with every aspect of Glide, such as Web, Data and Mobile iOS Engineering to ensure its Business continuity.

Engineering Manager & Argentina Coordinator Glide (US)

March 2019 - March 2021

Glide is a Real Estate Transaction Management Software, designed to help property managers fill forms, electronically sign documents, ensure compliance and make TCs and Agents lives easier. I weared many hats: Software Engineer, Engineering Manager and Argentina Coordinator.

- I was the first hire of Glide in Argentina and drove the growth of the team up to 10 people.
- I ran a production application with ~6k daily active users with high availability while keeping costs to a budget.
- Engineered different features of the Glide Application using Python, NodeJS and React.

Founder & Director

April 2017 - February 2019

Codexia (Argentina)

I Co-founded a small development agency, completely managing two projects including a small team of 3 Engineers. We successfully delivered three customer-facing products based on my proven stack composed of LoopbackJS (back end) + PostgreSQL (database), Angular + Material Design (web front end) and NativeScript for mobile apps when needed.

СТО

November 2017 - February 2019

TuCuota.Online (Argentina)

I laid the foundations of a system meant to help connect Lenders with Borrowers through retail stores. The proof of concept we came up with made us with the 2nd prize at a competition for Financial startups organized by the Central Bank of Argentina: http://www.bcra.gov.ar/noticias/El-directorio-y-ganadores-PIF.asp

Senior Software Engineer

PayrollPanda (Malaysia)

I worked on their two products: PayrollPanda and Jibble. Both were based on NodeJS, MongoDB and Backbone. Some important things I've accomplished:

- Simplified architecture with the replacement of a RabbitMQ instance with a much simpler job scheduler (Agenda).
- Introduced automated tests and a reliable build and deploy process to Heroku through Travis CI Server.

Software Engineer

May 2015 - March 2016

GreyStar Solutions / Zija (US)

Perl Developer. I fixed bugs, implemented new features and made some recommendations to modernize a rather old-styled MLM (multi-level marketing) system written in Perl and using MySQL.

Software Engineer

November 2013 - May 2015

Onapsis (Argentina)

Being the frontend architect and lead developer for Onapsis (Yeoman, Grunt, Bower, RequireJS, BackboneJS, jQuery) I created the first version of the modern FE for their main product.

Software Engineer

May 2012 - October 2013

CuatroGC (Argentina)

Along with three friends we launched a small startup.

I was PM and Developer on a project: Dingo: An online Bingo game engine 100% written in Javascript. Technologies involved: NodeJS, ExpressJS, BackboneJS, Twitter Bootstrap.

Software Engineer

May 2009 - April 2012

Bet3000 (Germany)

Sports betting company based in Munich, Germany.

- I worked as a Full-stack Engineer. Added complexity because of the big amount of db transactions in real time that the site supports (MySQL) due to live bets (Perl + MySQL + PrototypeJS + jQuery).
- I proposed Chef as an automated tool to manage Kiosk terminals spread all over Germany that we implemented with the DevOps team. Still being used.

Different Software Engineer and SysAdmin roles

February 1999 - April 2009

During this period I had 7 different roles where a few accomplishments that stand out are:

- Developed a client-side app for an Internet Kiosk App using Mono (.NET) on Linux
- Migrated root nameserver for the .ar zone from OpenBSD to FreeBSD.
- Deployed Y2K patches on Sun Solaris Servers

EDUCATION

4-year Bachelor in Information Systems at the Universidad Tecnológica Nacional.